<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Pain and Suffering</title>
        <link>https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Pain and Suffering</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 20:51:45 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Soul for sale! Tips for cyber employment, but it&#39;ll cost you</title>
            <link>https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/2023/07/soul-for-sale-tips-for-cyber-employment-but-itll-cost-you/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 20:51:45 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/2023/07/soul-for-sale-tips-for-cyber-employment-but-itll-cost-you/</guid>
            <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s another blog post on how to get a job in cyber. You have seen an abundance of different tips on Linkedin, professors and colleagues. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, they&amp;rsquo;re good and even work. But in my opinion, most of those tips are copied and pasted from HR and then telephoned throughout the industry. Below is what works for me and what has worked for people I have passed on to.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here&rsquo;s another blog post on how to get a job in cyber. You have seen an abundance of different tips on Linkedin, professors and colleagues. Don&rsquo;t get me wrong, they&rsquo;re good and even work. But in my opinion, most of those tips are copied and pasted from HR and then telephoned throughout the industry. Below is what works for me and what has worked for people I have passed on to. So, more ways to confuse yourself.</p>
<p>Getting A Job In Cyber:</p>
<p>Starting from students all the way to early professionals and career switches.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Internships as soon as possible (target for after sophomore year)
For the college students out there, please start applying for internships every year. Start in septemeber when the semester ends and you might get something in December or Summer of next year. Hands on experience is everything here. There is no alternative to real world exp.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Apply early (Target for September of senior year)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>As for when to be applying for jobs I say your Senior year September. I have talked to a lot of schools and presented to classes recently and the most common question I get is this. Some seniors wait till April or May to apply which is not ideal due the state of the industry, how long interview processes take and other factors. For anyone that has applied for jobs we all know it takes 3-8 months. For the folks that need sponsorship youu should be applying like crazy and super early. For internationals it&rsquo;s going to be difficult since a lot of orgs wont put in the funding for your visa or some may need security clearence. Dont set yourself up for failure and apply early.</p>
<ul>
<li>Networking<br>
Use your mom&rsquo;s coworkers, friends of a friend, that one professor that you dont really like but you know they have access to a tons of people. What alot of what me and friends did in college was search our Alum on linkeding and connect with them. Saying &ldquo;Hey I see you are an alumn of X I would love to connect with you. I was interested in opportunities at [where alumn works], and noticed you work here. I would like to learn about the work culture and what a typical day is like. &quot;</li>
</ul>
<p>-Personal Projects
If you are working in the tech industry its ideal that you have personal projects under your belt. Doesn&rsquo;t have to be building your own C2 Framework level but just something that shows the employer you want to be here. I reviewed a resume a while back and all they had was personal projects that acted like work experience. The resume overall needed work but to me as a techy I can tell that they are passionate about the work. Show your worth, a resume can only do so much. Its a new age of content, create youtube shorts, blogs or keep it simple and have a  github repo. Remember a business is putting resources and money into you. How can you help the company?</p>
<ul>
<li>Certifications
I am the wrong person to talk to about certs because as someone that hires, interviews and has been part of the student grind, I think certs are meh. Some people like being cert hunters with all the certs listed in their email, others just want to pass the test (but cant retain the knowledge), others do a mix of both (pass and learn).</li>
</ul>
<p>APPLY APPLY APPLY
Please dont let rejections affect you negatively
*show picture of my excel sheet
this is all the jobs i applied to I only got one offer out of college.</p>
<p>The reason the title says &ldquo;it&rsquo;ll cost you&rdquo; is due to the grind. You will first feel motivated, then after rejections, tired, then possibly anger. Then you might be on this really hot streak of applying every week then stopped. Its a rollercoaster, applying&hellip;.sorry looking for a job and the work that comes with it, is a job intself.</p>
<p>Have fun and if you have questions or want to chat reach out!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>C@reer_0pportun1ti3s</title>
            <link>https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/2023/07/c@reer_0pportun1ti3s/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 21:14:36 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://Stealthyunic0rn.github.io/posts/2023/07/c@reer_0pportun1ti3s/</guid>
            <description>If you ask a bunch of college students what cybersecurity is or the industry&amp;rsquo;s opportunities, they will most likely say hackers. They probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know what pentesters are. At least, that&amp;rsquo;s what I thought when I was in college. Starting out in this field, I was open to many opportunities and learned about many new roles. My first internship was creating policies for the organization, and I quickly realized the &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; side wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you ask a bunch of college students what cybersecurity is or the industry&rsquo;s opportunities, they will most likely say hackers. They probably wouldn&rsquo;t know what pentesters are. At least, that&rsquo;s what I thought when I was in college. Starting out in this field, I was open to many opportunities and learned about many new roles. My first internship was creating policies for the organization, and I quickly realized the &ldquo;business&rdquo; side wasn&rsquo;t for me.</p>
<p>I hate hearing new folks or students say, &ldquo;I&rsquo;m not technical enough&rdquo; or &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t want to be a hacker,&rdquo; because I know there is more than that. If you want to be in the business, you will play a critical role in the organization, and a skilled individual will definitely be sought after. The same goes for the technical side. If you are like me and want to be a techy, then you will have vital roles; however, you will also have the fluidity of wearing and learning multiple skills that bleed into each other&hellip;in my opinion.
It is also very common for people to switch sides or do both sides of the house. Below is a small infographic of the different roles and sub-roles one can take.</p>
<p><img src="/post_images/CyberRoles.png" alt="Career Chart"></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
